[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
The target's just
a small-time reporter.
Don't underestimate
your line of work.
Handle this one yourself.
Take care of that
Salvador Manalo guy,
scare him, rob him.
Why are you giving this
to the newbies?
It's just insulting
that this job is so easy.
This agent, lady agent,
very good acting!
She fooled me!
She won't stop until
I get pinned on this case.
You broke the protocol
of your agency?!
You're ruining my legacy!
The moment you tarnish my name,
I'll disown you as my daughter.
You shouldn't have to experience
a life like this.
When you were a child,
our life was luxurious.
When I saw the gold,
I got blinded by greed.
I forgot all my promises
to Ricardo.
My only thought was, "I'm going
to get rich and win your mom."
- [YOUNG GABO] Yay!
- [YOUNG RUDY] Daddy's coming!
- You can't catch me!
- Gabo! Gabo!
Hurry! Daddy's right behind you!
[GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING]
[GABO] The joy we felt
whenever we're together,
the love and joy
you've given me is priceless.
[YOUNG GABO] I love you, mommy.
[YOUNG BELINDA] I love you!
[YOUNG RUDY] W hy did you
do that?
[YOUNG BELINDA SIGHS]
It isn't right to punch others,
Gabriel.
But the kids who picked a fight
with his friends are bullies.
That's why Gabriel
just helped them, right?
Still, you shouldn't
have punched them.
You can't grow up
to be a troublemaker.
Do you understand?
Yes...
[YOUNG BELINDA] It's okay.
I'll take it from here.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Dear, your daddy is right.
If you can avoid
getting into any trouble,
stir away from it, okay?
But I'm not saying
that you should just accept
the injustices you see
happening around you.
If you know that you're
in the right, fight back.
- Okay...
- Come here, my baby.
- Position!
- [YOUNG GABO GRUNTING]
Down!
[GRUNTING] Upper!
-[YOUNG RUDY] Love, how's Gabo?
- Look.
He's being taught how to do
arnis and karate.
[GABO] You and mother were
the ones who taught me
how to fight and defend myself
as well as to help
those who are in need.
- Here he comes!
- [YOUNG GABO] Ha!
- [BLOWS LANDING]
- [BOTH GRUNTING]
- [THUDS]
- My son is the best!
- You hit me!
- Come here, you!
- [EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING]
- [YOUNG BELINDA LAUGHS]
- [LAUGHTER]
- You, guys!
You got this, son!
Don't give up!
[YOUNG BELINDA] But you have
to remember.
One day...
you'll be left all alone.
You'll have to face
and fight all of your fears.
[ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, wow.
Happy anniversary, love.
[SIGHS] You forgot?
Forgot what, love?
Our anniversary!
Love, it's not our anniversary.
Today was the day we met.
[GROANS]
I didn't know we have
multiple anniversaries, love.
The only one I remember
is our wedding anniversary.
With all of the days
I spend with you,
with you by my side,
- Hmm?
- I treat all of those
as our anniversary.
[YOUNG BELINDA LAUGHS]
You don't get tired of it?
[BOTH LAUGH]
Never, even if we spend
millions of years together.
Really?
[YOUNG RUDY]
You're the only Belinda...
I'll ever lay my eyes upon.
Love...
you get cornier...
as the days go by!
That's because as the days
go by,
[YOUNG BELINDA]
Mm-hmm?
my love for you grows even more.
I love, love, love
you so much too.
Thank you for the life
you've given me and Gabriel.
If I were to be reborn again,
I'd still choose you to spend
the rest of my life with.
[RUDY] In those eight years,
ever since you were born, Gabo,
it was as if we were all
on cloud nine.
[GABO] I remember
everything, Pa.
Those were the happiest days
of our lives.
[YOUNG GABO] I love you,
mommy and daddy!
[YOUNG BELINDA]
We love you too, son.
[RUDY] I prayed everyday...
that those happy days
would never come to an end.
But still, my sin haunts me.
- [TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [ENGINES REVVING]
[CAR DOORS OPENING]
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
[CAR DOORS CLOSING]
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[HURRIED FOOTSTEPS]
Sir! Sir!
There are people outside!
I think they're cops!
Tell our people
that no matter what,
- don't let them in.
- Yes, sir!
[GUN COCKS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Who are you? What do you need?!
Where is Rudy?
We are looking for Rudy.
No one's here.
We know Rudy's in there.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SPITS]
Rudy!
Show yourself, bastard
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR SLIDES OPEN]
[GRUNTING]
[CLICKING]
[DRAWER SLAMS OPEN]
Leave! I told you,
there's no one here!
There's no one, huh?
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [BLOOD GUSHING]
- [GATE SLAMS OPEN]
- [GUNSHOTS]
[GATE CREAKING OPEN]
- [RAPID GUNFIRE]
- [GUNSHOTS]
[YOUNG BELINDA] Rudy, I've
prepared what you asked for--
Wh--
- [THUDS]
- Rudy, what is all this?
Where did you get
all this gold from?
- [RAPID GUNFIRE]
- [BULLETS RICOCHETING]
Love, forgive me
for keeping this from you.
I was able to become rich
because of the gold I dug.
Is that why Ricardo's here?
Huh?
Is that why he's storming us?
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [MAN GROANS]
Ricardo and I were supposed
to share this between us
but... I got greedy. [PANTING]
I took all of it.
I ran away from him.
Love, I did it because I want
to give you everything.
- Rudy...
- But now,
my sins are coming back
to bite me.
We've been together
all these years
and you've kept this from me?!
You lied to me and now even
your son is in danger!
- [SLAP LANDS]
- [YOUNG BELINDA GRUNTS]
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Mommy, Daddy,
why are you fighting?
- Let's go, son.
- Wait, help me with the gold.
I don't care about any of those!
Let's go.
Rudy!
[YOUNG BELINDA CRYING]
Love, wait! Please wait, love!
Please forgive me for what
I did, love.
[CRYING] I love you two so much.
- Daddy...
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GUNSHOT]
[GRIM MUSIC PLAYING]
You bastard, Rudy!
[KICKS ON DOOR]
Run! Just run!
- [SCREAMING]
- [GUNSHOTS]
[YOUNG RUDY] Get down!
Come on, hurry!
[YOUNG RUDY] Quick, hide now.
Love, run away now, quick!
[GUNSHOTS]
Mommy...
- [GUNSHOTS CONTINUE]
- [GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES]
[BODY THUDS]
Here is the treasure!
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES]
[FAINT GUNFIRE IN DISTANCE]
[WHIMPERS]
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [WHIMPERING]
Rudy!
[GUNSHOTS]
[YOUNG BELINDA] Over here!
[SOBBING]
[WHIMPERING SOFTLY]
Is this what you want?!
Just take it, then!
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [BODY THUDDING]
[SOBS]
[GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES]
Sir, he's gone.
He's dead.
[GOLD BARS CLINKING]
Find out where the rest
of the gold is hidden.
[MAN] Yes, sir.
[GUN CLICKS]
Belinda and I
are not done yet.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[YOUNG GABO CRYING]
Gabriel. Gabriel, listen to me.
Listen to Mommy, okay?
Shh.
Just stay here.
Don't go anywhere, okay?
Mommy loves you so much.
No matter what happens,
always stay good.
Don't forget everything
I taught you, okay?
[CRYING] Okay, Mommy.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
[CRYING] Mommy.
[BELINDA] I love you so much.
- [YOUNG GABO CRYING]
- [BELINDA SHUSHING]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- Just stay here. Hide here.
- Mommy.
Don't follow me, okay?
Just stay here.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Ricardo!
Ricardo, have mercy
on my family.
Take me instead. Take me.
Please don't hurt them.
Ricardo, please.
- Aah!
- Damn you!
[BELINDA WHIMPERS]
[CRYING] Mommy!
[WHIMPERS] Ricardo.
I can't believe you chose
that dirt-poor Rudy!
[YOUNG RICARDO
GRUNTS IN ANGER]
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [BELINDA GROANS]
[CRYING]
Ricardo, please.
I'm begging you.
Ricardo, have mercy on us.
[BELINDA CRYING]
Please, I'm begging you.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [GUNSHOT]
- [CRYING]
[GABO] I saw how Mama died.
Those bastards!
I won't stop until I get
justice for Mama's death.
[MUFFLED SOBS]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[MAN] Sir! Sir!
We found the gold!
Sir, let's go.
Sir.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MUSIC FADES]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
Mommy.
Belinda.
- [SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [YOUNG GABO CRYING]
- [YOUNG RUDY CRYING]
- [YOUNG GABO] Mommy.
- [YOUNG RUDY] Sorry.
Love, I'm-- I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me, love.
[YOUNG GABO AND YOUNG
RUDY CRYING]
I'm sorry.
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[YOUNG GABO CRYING]
[YOUNG GABO] Mommy.
[YOUNG GABO AND YOUNG
RUDY CRYING]
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[YOUNG RUDY]
From now on...
it's just the two of us.
But don't worry, son.
I will never abandon you.
I won't allow the two of us
to be separated.
Don't forget that, okay?
[GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING]
[YOUNG GABO CRYING]
[YOUNG GABO] Bye, Mommy.
[GLOOMY MUSIC CONTINUES]
That gold...
is the reason
we lost everything.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Is it because
of that cop, Pa?
Is it because of that cop
who killed my mother?
Gabo...
It's best that you
don't know.
You're on the right
path now.
Don't be tempted
to do something wrong.
I made a lot of mistakes
in the past.
But I know that
I raised you well.
You have a good heart, Gabo.
You're not like me.
Pa...
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I need to find that cop.
He has to pay
for what he did to my mother.
And what he did to you.
He's the reason
we are suffering today.
I need to find him!
Ga--Gabo.
Gabo!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ISOBEL] Ricardo.
Can we talk about Sam?
[MUG CLATTERS]
[SIGHS] Okay.
What about Sam?
Our daughter grew up smart.
As parents, we're here
to guide, not dictate her.
What's wrong
with you, Isobel?
Why are you
always defending her?
Her disobedience
in the workplace protocol
only shows that she lacks
discipline and respect
to those superior to her.
[ISOBEL] She doesn't mean
to disrespect you,
dishonor you, to hurt you.
She's actually protecting
your name!
Well, that's not how I see it,
[ISOBEL] Because you're being
so close-minded.
You always snap at her!
Me?
Close-minded?
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[MAX] So,
are you enjoying this?
Your parents are arguing
first thing in the morning.
Of course not.
Yes, because this is the result
of your stubbornness.
I already handled the problem.
I just didn't know--
That you would get caught?
Sam, are you not thinking?
That's our father!
If you listened to him when
he told you to lie low,
they wouldn't
be arguing like this.
Isobel, our children were born
into a policeman's family.
To a General!
My reputation is not ordinary,
so my demands for them
to protect my name
isn't ordinary either!
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SIGHS]
- Mommy?
- Oh, Sam.
I'm sorry.
You're arguing about me again.
What? No.
Your father has a lot in mind.
I think it's because they're
hosting a party for Generals.
Don't worry about it.
It's okay.
Mom.
You're always defending him.
And you always defend me.
Maybe it's time we should be
responsible with our actions.
Especially me.
That was just the only way
I could think of
so that everything
wouldn't get worse.
Mom, I'm sorry.
I'll fix all the problems
I've caused.
I'll fix it.
I believe you can, Sam.
I need to go, mom.
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SIGHS]
[DJANGO] Hey.
Par queen straight.
Full ace.
[MAN] I lost.
- [LAUGHTER]
- Isn't that Django?
- [ROMY] Why is he still here?
- Oh, I'm so happy.
- [DJANGO LAUGHS]
- [PAQUITO] Django.
Shouldn't you guys
be leaving already?
Aren't you supposed to ambush
the reporter today?
Pa.
That's already taken care of.
Django, every move
we make is important.
We could lose everything if
you make even just one mistake.
Pa, I already
handled it last night.
Relax.
[PAQUITO] As you should!
If we mess up this job that
Umali is making us do,
we're going to lose
a lot of money!
So do a good job!
Go! Get a move on!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- Hey!
- Boss.
Get a move on it.
Now!
These two
are the bad influence.
- [CASTOR] Sir.
- [SEBASTIAN] Hmm?
What's the update?
Mr. Chan refuses to talk.
He won't speak because
you never saw any gold.
If it is proven that his
arrest was unauthorized
will the NCIA be held liable?
Nope. It's just you.
- Just us?
- Yeah.
Wow.
Thanks for the support.
Your operation was illegal.
There was no order
from the higher-ups.
For your information,
Ernesto,
we just supported Ma'am Sam.
I know that.
[KAREN] And we don't regret it.
Karen, why are you here?
- Is your wound healed?
- I feel restless at home.
I can't stop thinking
about Mr. Chan's case.
Guys, if Mr. Chan talks
to his lawyer,
he may file
a claim against you.
You had no warrant
when you arrested him.
He could also file
an administrative case.
Unless he cooperates with us.
He admits that he has
connections with Victor Zafra,
and if he points out
where the gold is.
If that happens, then
your actions have a legal basis.
If that's the case, then fine.
I'll make him confess.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
Sam, Sir Delgado
already warned you.
Ma'am.
Don't add
to your violations anymore.
We'll just prove to him
that catching
Mr. Chan wasn't a mistake.
If he needs to tell everything
he knows about Zafra,
then he'll do it.
Sam, hold on.
[CLEARS THROAT]
You can't stop me.
I know.
That's why I'm going with you.
Let's go.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[APPLAUDING]
You're very good.
You pretended to be a buyer.
You fooled me.
Look at you.
- Look at me.
- [CUFFS RATTLING]
How are you connected
to Victor Zafra?
What do you know about him?
He's in jail, right?
[CHUCKLES]
You'll end up with him
if you don't tell the truth.
Are you part of his group?
Where's the gold you have?
I will not tell you.
I don't know.
Those guys you fought
at the warehouse,
they were Victor Zafra's men,
weren't they?
Your life is in danger.
Listen, you don't know
who you're messing with.
The Zafras are killers.
They will kill you!
[LAUGHS]
I'm not scared of them!
[BORROMEO] Ma'am Sam
shouldn't have
interrogated Mr. Chan just yet.
I don't know if Sam is
determined or just stubborn.
[RALLOS] The review about her
on Mr. Chan's case
isn't even finished yet,
and here she goes again.
You know how Sam is.
She won't stop if she's
focused on it.
But right now,
she has too many violations.
I hope she gets something
out of Mr. Chan.
If not, then she's screwed
to Sir Delgado and Ma'am Pia.
[MR. CHAN] I will not talk.
[LAUGHS]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
Sir, here's the decision of the
Internal Affairs Department
regarding Jacinto's case.
Considering her service record,
is there a chance for her
to have a lighter sanction?
Based on our investigation,
that is the appropriate
disciplinary action.
Okay. Thank you very much.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Mm.
- Sir?
- Yes?
[DOOR CLOSES]
Do you know what your favorite
agent is doing right now?
Who?
Samantha!
She's in the
interrogation room right now...
...with Mr. Chan.
What?!
- I don't know!
- I know that you know...
...that your life is in danger
with Victor Zafra!
Do you understand that?
[SAM] How about this?
[SIGHS DEEPLY]
Give us information
and we'll give you
witness protection.
Yeah, fess up and cooperate.
[SAM] We can even
lighten your sentence.
Just fess up
and we'll help you.
You will use my word against me
to get out of trouble?
You are very desperate already.
B****!
When I'm asking you,
you better answer properly!
Well?!
You are not a good agent!
You are careless and worthless!
[SPITS]
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [GRUNTS]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
You--
Don't stop me!
You bastard!
- Jacinto!
- She hit me!
She hit me here! She hit me!
Sir, he was rude!
I was talking to him nicely--
- To my office! Now!
- She hit me! She hit me! Help!
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MAMENG] Good thing the doctors
agreed to let Rudy go home
and continue his recovery there.
Oh. Hey, Gabo.
Doctors said we can
take your father home.
Nothing's really impossible
by the grace of God.
Rudy, the doctors agreed
to let us take you home.
They just said to make sure
you take your prescribed meds.
Where's Gabo?
He's sitting outside.
You know, supposedly, a problem
was waiting for you at home.
What is it?
You know that bike?
The one that's owned
by a seaman?
Your son messed with it.
He almost lost it.
Good thing he got it back.
Since he got it back,
just let it slide.
Huh?
Well, what are we waiting for?
- Are you ready to go?
- Yeah, we're ready.
- Let's go?
- I'll help you change.
[GABRIEL] I grew up yearning
for a mother.
- [BELINDA] Gabriel, listen.
- [YOUNG GABO CRYING]
Listen to Mommy, okay?
Mommy loves you so much.
No matter what happens,
be kind, okay?
Remember everything
I taught you.
[YOUNG GABO CRYING]
Yes, Mommy.
[GABO] I grew up
feeling something was missing
because I lost my mother
as a child.
Mommy!
[GABO] And to this day,
we haven't received justice
for what they did to my mother.
Those cops caused me
so much suffering.
I'll make sure
to find out who they are.
I'll hunt them down
and get back at them
for my mother.
I'll make their families feel
the same pain and agony
I suffered for years.
I'll kill them all
and I will not spare
their families.
Admin put you
under preventive suspension.
Well-deserved!
I just did
what I thought was right.
You did what you wanted.
What? Are you going
to hit me, too?
I'm not going to sit here
and do nothing
while Samantha Jacinto
is out there.
I'll make her pay, Ma!
- You know what to do.
- I won't fight back!
I want you to make it spotless.
If you fail,
I'll put you all down.
Isn't Gabo supposed to
be with you? Where is he?
He's not yet here?
He left before us.
The seaman's coming today
to get his bike.
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE ROARS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
- If you only knew....
...the things Gabo went through.
- [KICK LANDS]
- What did he do this time?
Don't be like Gabo.
He's actually a good influence.
That's why we're following him.
- [BLOWS LANDING]
- [GRUNTING]
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [BODY THUDS]